My hair currently looks like the average
codebase that uses Redux.
And if I had a dollar for every time
someone asked me if they should learn Redux,
then I'd actually have enough money to
hire a decent developer to fix it.
This is a cause that's very near and dear
to my heart so I decided to make my
dreams a reality and code it up
shouldilearnredux.netlify.app
How it works is you can pay
one dollar to unlock the answer
of whether you should be learning Redux.
Underneath the hood, when you click the button
it will run a series of deep neural nets
that pipe into a machine learning model
which will then cross-reference against
some if-statements to analyze your
browser history and determine
whether you should be learning Redux.
This takes a little while to run for the
first time you click on the button
but it will cache the results after that for
subsequent presses
so I already paid myself a dollar and
I can show you guys the cache results for myself.
I got a big fat no and that's pretty
much the main reason why I don't use Redux.
Now the thing about machine learning is
it's not always right so what I want to
do in this video is discuss how I would
use Redux,
Recoil, Context and just how I view state
management in React in general.
In the average React app there's usually
three types of state.
And the most common one has to do with
just fetching data
and storing it from an API. And commonly
Redux is used for that.
Redux is just a general state management library
so everyone implements this differently.
But here's an example that is simple to
just give you an idea.
So we have a use effect hook which will
run after the first
render and just dispatch an action to
load some data from the API.
And then once that is loaded in,
it'll be stored in Redux
and just passed to this component.
Using Redux for this type of state
reminds me a lot of
making your own marinara sauce
from scratch.
If you're willing to put in the time and
the effort and you're actually good at cooking
then the end results can actually
be pretty good.
But if you're just okay at cooking or maybe
you're just surrounded with
a bunch of crappy sous chefs that
have terrible taste buds
make it too salty then you're just
going to be kind of left with
a bowl of spaghetti code and some
nasty marinara sauce on top.
Now don't worry
I'm not about to suggest you
go out and get yourself a jar of
marinara sauce.
I would never do that.
That stuff is crap.
But I am going to recommend you
head over to your grandma's house
who's got a giant pot of marinara sauce
that she made all from scratch.
That is just sitting there waiting for you.
She goes by a lot of names
depending on the type of API you have.
If you like GraphQL, some call her
Apollo or Relay.
If you like Rest she's known as
React Query or SWR.
But no matter what you call her, at the
end of the day you're going to get a
great tasting marinara sauce that is
specifically designed
for fetching and caching data from an API.
And your grandma made the entire thing
with fresh ingredients.
I'm sure there's some applications that
need like a custom setup,
but just for the average React App,
using a data fetching library that is
specifically designed for this type of state,
compared to a general state management
library, is going to save you
a lot of time and effort, and is what I
would recommend using.
The second type of state is what I call
local state and it's pretty much any
client-side state that just one component
or a few nearby components need access to.
For example you could
have a checkbox that you can take
on and off to hide and show something
in your UI.
And for this, I like to handle it with
just the built-in useState hook.
And then of course if things get more
complex or you have some more complex state,
there's also the useReducer hook.
And of course as the component evolves
and just your requirements change,
more components might need
access to that state.
And so you just lift it up to the highest level
and if the components that need the
state are just nearby you just pass it
down as props.
Otherwise it's not really local state
anymore and it goes into like the next
category which I can consider
"global" state.
I put global in parentheses because
it's not necessarily that this state
is used across like your entire application.
It just can be any state that you don't
feel like passing props all the way down to
or it just gets annoying to do that.
For example, you might have a
sidebar that sometimes you
want to hide, but sometimes you want to show,
and maybe the way that happens is
there's like a button in the header and
you press that. And so you want to be able to
control the sidebar from the header over
here. But then they're way far apart and
they're very far in the component tree.
For situations like this, I either like
to use React Context or just
whatever state management library
I'm liking best at the moment.
Currently, that happens to be Zustand
because I don't have to wrap my entire
React App in providers
which is kind of nice. But
honestly, there's a lot of good options
and just really comes down to whichever
state management library you like better.
And with this approach you're not going
to be handling a lot of state at all
with a state management library or React
Context. It's just going to be like a little
sprinkle on top. And then the majority of
your state is going to be handled by useState
in a data fetching library.
Now some of you may have noticed I have
yet to mention Recoil, and that is for
very good reason. I don't think recoil is
very necessary in the average React
application. I watched the video
introducing recoil and I thought to myself
hmm that is a really cool library. But
that is also a library specifically
designed for a Facebook problem. If I end
up having a problem like that
then yeah I'll give it a try. But until
then I just kind of put it on the back
burner. To circle back to the earlier
question of whether you should learn Redux,
I think if you can control the
technologies you are using on a project.
Then there are better options and
I wouldn't learn Redux.
But you just don't always have that luxury.
Even though Redux has kind of
fallen out of favor on social media,
there's still a lot of companies that
use it. And if you are a current React
developer or you're planning
on becoming one, you
are probably going to encounter Redux
somewhere in your career.
And so you are probably going to be
required to learn at some point,
although I would recommend to
procrastinate it as long as you can.
Anyway for those of you that end up using
Redux, anyway, I wish you the best of luck.
Give Redux Toolkit and maybe Redux Query a try.
Hopefully you don't get RSI
(Repetitive strain injury) from this.
And remember be very careful with Redux.
You do not want your codebase
looking like this.