Last year I made a video called technologies I'm learning in 2021.
I want to review the technologies I said I learned.
And see how I actually did and then tell you guys what I'm planning on learning in 2022.
Relay, the GraphQL client that is made by Facebook.
That's supposed to be awesome beast mode.
Everyone's telling me to try it out and I never got to it.
And I just kind of don't have a good excuse other than I didn't feel like it.
And I'm relatively happy with the GraphQL client that I'm using now Urql, so I would just continue to use that.
Should I give Relay a try? Yes.
Will it happen this year? To be honest, probably not but maybe,  possibly.
I did indeed try OVH I bought a VPS from them and it was great. But unfortunately, I bought it right when they had a fire.
And it went down and I was like, well snap, that's not good and I switched to Google Cloud.
Oh Elixir, I had a lot of fun with you in 2021.
I built an entire clubhouse clone backend using it.
It worked wonderfully like 95 of the time and I loved the language.
But I also died inside having to code with a dynamically typed language and that is the reason
why I am not coding an Elixir currently.
I still really like it I'll probably do some Elixir microservice things because,  like real time, decentralized,
that's not the right word, concurrent, something where you have lots of processes happening at once, Elixir is great at.
I really liked it and would happily do more of it.
Rust never really happened.
I was gonna do some smart contract stuff with Solana.
And I did dabble my two a little bit in but then I lost interest in Solana smart contracts and I was like
yeah I don't really feel like learning Rust anymore. I'll probably get to Rust eventually, but here's the thing
I just really don't have a good use case to learn it right now but when I have one then I'm gonna learn Rust.
But it's just not there yet.
Cloudflare is great I stick in front of everything that's pretty much it.
Rest apis were created by me in 2021 but what I ended up doing was just trying to recreate my experience in GraphQL
and generate types and do all that fun stuff and I realized that was dumb.
And so I just switched back to doing GraphQL apis.
I never created a component library just not really
feeling it I tried really hard to do a hardware project and
I thought of a really cool idea and I tried in my brain
to figure out what I would actually do
to make this happen and I could figure
out the sequence of logic but then
mapping that to the actual hardware
parts I'd have to buy and wiring it all up
was just something I could not be
bothered to do there's just not as many
resources on hardware as there is the
software and it's like the cost of like
trial and error is way more expensive
not even from a monetary point of view
but your time of like waiting for parts
to arrive trialing to see if the part
works and if it didn't
and ugh it just yeah it just never happened.
I do want to give it more tries in 2022 because
there's still like a really cool thing I want to build
I just need to have the willpower to want to try making
it again which I lost.
Now I want to talk about some
technologies that I used a lot in 2021
I mentioned Chakra in my last video and
how I like to use it to style React
components I'm not using that anymore
Tailwind is my go-to thing for styling
absolutely everything it is amazing for
productivity and I highly recommend it.
For GraphQL clients I am fully on the
Urql train right now I don't really
need the extra features that Apollo has
and I feel like it's just getting a little clunky.
Front frameworks still on React still like it
and that's pretty much what I'm using for everything.
TypeScript's my go-to language for just
full stack I like using it with node
I like using it on the front end it's great
I really like the language it's statically typed which is big for me
and I'm using it more than Elixir because of
that though I still see myself using
some Elixir for certain things.
Database PostgreSQL pretty standard fantastic use it for everything
I started using Prisma 2 with PostgreSQL
I still don't like that it does like way too many queries
if I tilt to update and return fields
it's not very optimized
but other than that the UX experience for development is very good
I really like it. React Native is what I'm using
to build all apps not going back to
native development and not using Flutter.
VSCode with Vim key bindings is the editor I'm using.
I did see Jetbrains create like a VSCode-like editor
and I might try that at some point but to be honest
I have zero complaints VSCode right now.
Aws has become the cloud that I use most
but there's not really good reason behind that.
And lastly, this is not really something I used a lot in 2021
but I did learn how to do smart contracts with solidity
and it's kind of gross because it just reminds me a lot of Java
but it is a thing I did. For 2022, the first thing
I'd like to do is learn more animation things.
If you've seen my previous projects you may see the lack of animations
that's because I just never was really comfortable with them
and I didn't know how to animate or what I wanted to animate
but now when I'm doing a voidpet, I kind of like sticking
animations in places and so I'm going to do more stuff related to animations.
Next this is a possibility it's not like confirmed
it's not a hundred percent
but I might do some Unity / 3d game dev.
It may not actually be with unity,
because I'm kind of enjoying building a game right now.
Voidpet is specifically going to be a web game for a while, so it may not need this.
But there may be a point where I want to.
Now for some reason I'm kind of in the mood to learn Terraform and Kubernetes.
And do like some fancy DevOps things.
I don't really have a good reason for you on this one other than I just kind of been in the mood for whatever reason.
Turborepo is something I think is going to be really easy to learn.
And it's just going to speed up my Yarn workspaces and
I just need to learn it and plug it into my things it probably is going to take like 10 minutes too.
Remix is a React framework that is kind of a competitor to Next.js
I'm going to be watching this and probably trying it out sometime this year. I'm excited to see Next.js actually have a competitor
because they really are competing against no one right now
so that's just gonna make the web dev environment better for everyone.
Lastly we got smart contracts, this is a very big maybe
I don't actually know if this is gonna happen
I just can't see myself not dabbling in them somewhere, but it may not be a deep thing.
Every time I've done smart contracts, I've kind of lost interest halfway through.
But it may happen, who knows?
There you go, those are my plans for 2022.
Let me know in the comments below what you're planning on learning.
Or if you have any recommendations for me I'm always happy to hear them.